<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Easy There Entropy</title>
    <link>https://ebuchman.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Easy There Entropy</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ebuchman.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Socially Responsible Investing</title>
      <link>https://ebuchman.github.io/posts/socially-responsible-investing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ebuchman.github.io/posts/socially-responsible-investing/</guid>
      <description>This is not investment advice. Do your own research. The analyses here are based on vague subjective notions of social responsibility that are likely to be nonsense anyways. They do not account at all for the potential profitability of the companies mentioned or any kind or ROI. Disclosure of my own positions is incomplete at best.
For years I&amp;rsquo;ve felt that the vast majority of publicly available securities represent fundamentally socially irresponsible behaviour (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reconsidering the Factors of Production</title>
      <link>https://ebuchman.github.io/posts/factors-of-production/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ebuchman.github.io/posts/factors-of-production/</guid>
      <description>The great tragedy of mainstream, neoclassical economics is that, in trying to transform the Classical political-economy of the 19th century into a more mathematical science of economics, it butchered its political and moral foundation.
It all started with a good idea - from Menger, Jevons, and Walras - of the subjective nature of value and the marginal utility of goods. The &amp;ldquo;marginal revolution&amp;rdquo;, as we know it today, enabled supply and demand to be treated analytically with the tools of calculus, and for equations to be solved that maximize utility and minimize costs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Local Money and Liquidity Saving</title>
      <link>https://ebuchman.github.io/posts/local-money-liquidity-saving/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ebuchman.github.io/posts/local-money-liquidity-saving/</guid>
      <description>Local Money Systems As you may know, I&amp;rsquo;m quite enchanted with the idea of local money systems - moneys designed to facilitate local economic organization and trade. There&amp;rsquo;s a nice overview in Bernard Lietar&amp;rsquo;s Creating Wealth. I think they&amp;rsquo;re the best application of blockchain tech and the best hope for a sustainable civilization.
I expect that progress in blockchain tech and tokenomic primitives (like bonding curves) will revolutionize the field of Optimum Currency Areas and paint a path towards a more sustainable theory of international monetary economics grounded in self-sufficient local economies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Critique of MMT from a Monetary Localist</title>
      <link>https://ebuchman.github.io/posts/mmt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ebuchman.github.io/posts/mmt/</guid>
      <description>Disclaimer: This critique is based almost entirely on a reading of Stephanie Kelton&amp;rsquo;s popularization of MMT, The Deficit Myth. I have yet to really dive into the MMT academic literature.
MMT So it turns out, quite to my delight, there&amp;rsquo;s some interesting stuff in Modern Monetary Theory (MMT). For someone who believes that abuse of the money printer is the source of so much ill in society, this was somewhat surprising, if not terrifying, since MMT appears to be a licence to crank the printer to 11.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crypto Needs to Engage With the World</title>
      <link>https://ebuchman.github.io/posts/crypto-needs-to-engage-with-the-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ebuchman.github.io/posts/crypto-needs-to-engage-with-the-world/</guid>
      <description>I wrote an op-ed in Coindesk, called Crypto Needs to Engage With the World.
It&amp;rsquo;s basically an unrolled version of my crypto thesis tweet thread.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Modest Mongolian</title>
      <link>https://ebuchman.github.io/posts/2020-04-25-modest-mongolian/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ebuchman.github.io/posts/2020-04-25-modest-mongolian/</guid>
      <description>The Story of Civilization The story of human civilization begins around 10k years ago in the dawn of agricultural societies, in a new relationship between humans and land. Agriculture transformed the nature of land from external environment into direct extension of the human body and society; from something to contend with into something to protect.
The story is often told, quite wonderfully, in maps; the changing borders of unified claims on land in the form of empires that ebb and flow across the rugged surface of the Earth over the last few thousand years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy 1st Birthday Cosmos!</title>
      <link>https://ebuchman.github.io/posts/2020-03-13-happy-1st-birthday-cosmos/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ebuchman.github.io/posts/2020-03-13-happy-1st-birthday-cosmos/</guid>
      <description>One whole year ago today, the Cosmos community made history with the successful decentralized launch of the Gaia blockchain, also known as the Cosmos Hub. After being &amp;ldquo;two months away&amp;rdquo; from launch for about 16 months, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t even begin to describe the joy of seeing our incredible community of validators launch Gaia into the world. I checked block explorers many times each day, in complete awe that this software we had spent years building was actually running in a production economic environment; that it was making blocks every ~6 seconds; that it hadn&amp;rsquo;t completely fallen over.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GCUOF</title>
      <link>https://ebuchman.github.io/posts/2019-02-22-gcuof/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ebuchman.github.io/posts/2019-02-22-gcuof/</guid>
      <description>This is an ode to the Guelph Center for Urban Organic Farming, an organic farm located on the University of Guelph campus, where I fell in love with gardening and discovered that permaculture can feed the world.
The Guelph Center for Urban Organic Farming is a sanctuary. A botanical paradise. A fantasy realm in our own backyard. It is a stunning beacon of productivity; a shining ray of sustainable capacity; a testament to the permacultural principles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software Collaboration, Part I</title>
      <link>https://ebuchman.github.io/posts/2019-01-26-software-collab-part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 11:39:36 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ebuchman.github.io/posts/2019-01-26-software-collab-part1/</guid>
      <description>Modern distributed software development marks the pinacle of text-based collaboration. A global web of internet connected humans, of varying geopolitical and educational background, working for different companies or none at all, composing tapestries of textual repositories that give rise to our entire digital society.
The essential feature of software development today is distributed version control, or, the &amp;ldquo;management of changes across agents&amp;rdquo;. This is an apt description of what societies, too, are collectively tasked with doing, and probably has a lot to do with why software is eating the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Economic Organisms</title>
      <link>https://ebuchman.github.io/posts/2019-01-20-economic-organisms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ebuchman.github.io/posts/2019-01-20-economic-organisms/</guid>
      <description>Life Socioeconomic systems may be conceived in the same vein as organisms: driven, replicated, non-equilibrium systems in a landscape of steady-states. Lifetimes and sustainability in such systems are parameterized by the capacity to represent and predict driving signals, and to use the energy contained in such signals to replicate successfully.
Driving signals are the cycles of availability of input energy that drive systems out of equilibrium. Driven systems favour the formation of well-organized, low-entropy structures to the extent that they are better able than high-entropy forms to store, utilize, and ultimately dissipate input energy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bitcoin Turns 10</title>
      <link>https://ebuchman.github.io/posts/2019-01-03-bitcoin-turns-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 21:14:08 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ebuchman.github.io/posts/2019-01-03-bitcoin-turns-10/</guid>
      <description>On January 3rd, 2009, the great mother Goddess of cryptoeconomics, Satoshi Nakamoto, birthed her baby Bitcoin into the world. 10 years later, Bitcoin is booming, awakening cavalries of latent innovative energy and catalyzing radical new approaches to socioeconomic systems.
Bitcoin and its ilk are pushing the boundaries of critical fields of study, from fault tolerant distributed computing, to cryptography, mechanism design, and formal verification. The impact of these developments will be felt for generations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World</title>
      <link>https://ebuchman.github.io/posts/2019-01-01-hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 11:39:36 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ebuchman.github.io/posts/2019-01-01-hello-world/</guid>
      <description>I love writing, and I want to commit to doing more of it. Once upon a time I had a good cadence going on Blogspot, and when that dropped off, I eventually picked up again on Wordpress. But it&amp;rsquo;s been a while. Now I plan to write in Vim and publish on Github while letting Hugo do the hard work of beautifying, unless you can convince me of something better.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://ebuchman.github.io/origin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ebuchman.github.io/origin/</guid>
      <description>I started undergrad at the University of Toronto double majoring in Neuroscience and Religion. I was especially inspired by Julian Jaynes&amp;rsquo; [The Origin of Consciousness in the Breakdown of the Bicameral Mind]. I later switched to the University of Guelph, which had neither a program in Neuroscience nor Religion. After a semester or two I panicked about having not really done any math or programming since high school, so I started taking courses in math, physics, and programming, along with various cell biology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://ebuchman.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ebuchman.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi! I&amp;rsquo;m Ethan Buchman. I grew up in Toronto, Canada, but spent many years in lovely Guelph. I work in software, research, education, and the garden.
I co-founded the Cosmos and Tendermint projects, which I still work on, as CEO of Informal Systems and President of the Interchain Foundation.
I&amp;rsquo;m also an associate at the Creative Destruction Lab.
I&amp;rsquo;m active on twitter, where I refer to myself as an Internet BioPhysicist, Sustainability Existentialist, Monetary Localist, and PlainText Evangelist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Financial Interests</title>
      <link>https://ebuchman.github.io/investments/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ebuchman.github.io/investments/</guid>
      <description>This is a record of my financial interests.
As an angel investor, my primary focus is food security and sustainability. My secondary focus is fintech/legaltech.
Some of the investments listed below are held through companies I control.
My Companies These are companies I hold stock in as a founder or past/current employee.
 Informal Systems Inc. - Verifiable Distributed Systems and Organizations Cephalopod Equipment Corp - Proof of Stake Validator All in Bits Inc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Media</title>
      <link>https://ebuchman.github.io/media/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ebuchman.github.io/media/</guid>
      <description>Podcasts 2021-05: Real Vision Crypto - Envisioning a Proof of Stake Alternative with Ethan Buchman, co-founder of Cosmos
2021-02: The Pomp Podcast - Ethan Buchman on Standardization And Interoperability
2021-02: CMCC Global - Interview with Ethan Buchman, Co-founder of Cosmos
2020-10: Untold Stories - Reinventing Governance &amp;amp; Crypto Social Experiments
2020-09: Fintech Impact - Cosmos with Ethan Buchman
2020-06: Hashing it Out - Informal Systems with Ethan Buchman
2020-06: Citizen Cosmos - Ethan Buchman, the now and then of Cosmos</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Media</title>
      <link>https://ebuchman.github.io/media2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ebuchman.github.io/media2/</guid>
      <description>Podcasts 2021-05: Real Vision Crypto - Envisioning a Proof of Stake Alternative with Ethan Buchman, co-founder of Cosmos
2021-02: The Pomp Podcast - Ethan Buchman on Standardization And Interoperability
2021-02: CMCC Global - Interview with Ethan Buchman, Co-founder of Cosmos
2020-10: Untold Stories - Reinventing Governance &amp;amp; Crypto Social Experiments
2020-09: Fintech Impact - Cosmos with Ethan Buchman
2020-06: Hashing it Out - Informal Systems with Ethan Buchman
2020-06: Citizen Cosmos - Ethan Buchman, the now and then of Cosmos</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Papers</title>
      <link>https://ebuchman.github.io/papers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ebuchman.github.io/papers/</guid>
      <description> Reflections on Metaphor and the Nature of Mind Cosmos: A Network of Blockchains The Latest Gossip on BFT Understanding Minimum Probability Flow for RBMs
 Underfit
 Bachelors Thesis
 Masters Thesis
 Butanol
 other &amp;hellip; ?
  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>