<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Easy There Entropy</title>
    <link>https://ebuchman.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Easy There Entropy</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ebuchman.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy 1st Birthday Cosmos!</title>
      <link>https://ebuchman.github.io/posts/2020-03-13-happy-1st-birthday-cosmos/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ebuchman.github.io/posts/2020-03-13-happy-1st-birthday-cosmos/</guid>
      <description>One whole year ago today, the Cosmos community made history with the successful decentralized launch of the Gaia blockchain, also known as the Cosmos Hub. After being &amp;ldquo;two months away&amp;rdquo; from launch for about 16 months, I can&amp;rsquo;t even begin to describe the joy of seeing our incredible community of validators launch Gaia into the world. I checked block explorers many times each day, in complete awe that this software we had spent years building was actually running in a production economic environment; that it was making blocks every ~6 seconds; that it hadn&amp;rsquo;t completely fallen over.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GCUOF</title>
      <link>https://ebuchman.github.io/posts/2019-02-22-gcuof/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ebuchman.github.io/posts/2019-02-22-gcuof/</guid>
      <description>This is an ode to the Guelph Center for Urban Organic Farming, an organic farm located on the University of Guelph campus, where I fell in love with gardening and discovered that permaculture can feed the world.
The Guelph Center for Urban Organic Farming is a sanctuary. A botanical paradise. A fantasy realm in our own backyard. It is a stunning beacon of productivity; a shining ray of sustainable capacity; a testament to the permacultural principles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software Collaboration, Part I</title>
      <link>https://ebuchman.github.io/posts/2019-01-26-software-collab-part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 11:39:36 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ebuchman.github.io/posts/2019-01-26-software-collab-part1/</guid>
      <description>Modern distributed software development marks the pinacle of text-based collaboration. A global web of internet connected humans, of varying geopolitical and educational background, working for different companies or none at all, composing tapestries of textual repositories that give rise to our entire digital society.
The essential feature of software development today is distributed version control, or, the &amp;ldquo;management of changes across agents&amp;rdquo;. This is an apt description of what societies, too, are collectively tasked with doing, and probably has a lot to do with why software is eating the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Economic Organisms</title>
      <link>https://ebuchman.github.io/posts/2019-01-20-economic-organisms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ebuchman.github.io/posts/2019-01-20-economic-organisms/</guid>
      <description>Life Socioeconomic systems may be conceived in the same vein as organisms: driven, replicated, non-equilibrium systems in a landscape of steady-states. Lifetimes and sustainability in such systems are parameterized by the capacity to represent and predict driving signals, and to use the energy contained in such signals to replicate successfully.
Driving signals are the cycles of availability of input energy that drive systems out of equilibrium. Driven systems favour the formation of well-organized, low-entropy structures to the extent that they are better able than high-entropy forms to store, utilize, and ultimately dissipate input energy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bitcoin Turns 10</title>
      <link>https://ebuchman.github.io/posts/2019-01-03-bitcoin-turns-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 21:14:08 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ebuchman.github.io/posts/2019-01-03-bitcoin-turns-10/</guid>
      <description>On January 3rd, 2009, the great mother Goddess of cryptoeconomics, Satoshi Nakamoto, birthed her baby Bitcoin into the world. 10 years later, Bitcoin is booming, awakening cavalries of latent innovative energy and catalyzing radical new approaches to socioeconomic systems.
Bitcoin and its ilk are pushing the boundaries of critical fields of study, from fault tolerant distributed computing, to cryptography, mechanism design, and formal verification. The impact of these developments will be felt for generations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World</title>
      <link>https://ebuchman.github.io/posts/2019-01-01-hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 11:39:36 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ebuchman.github.io/posts/2019-01-01-hello-world/</guid>
      <description>I love writing, and I want to commit to doing more of it. Once upon a time I had a good cadence going on Blogspot, and when that dropped off, I eventually picked up again on Wordpress. But it&amp;rsquo;s been a while. Now I plan to write in Vim and publish on Github while letting Hugo do the hard work of beautifying, unless you can convince me of something better.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://ebuchman.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ebuchman.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>I work in software, research, education, and the garden.
The following more or less sum me up:
 &amp;ldquo;There is nothing in a caterpillar that tells you it&amp;rsquo;s going to be a butterfly.&amp;rdquo;
- Buckminster Fuller
  &amp;ldquo;There are no passengers on spaceship earth. We are all crew.&amp;rdquo;
- Marshall McLuhan
  &amp;ldquo;Human beings were invented by water as a device for transporting itself from one place to another.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recordings</title>
      <link>https://ebuchman.github.io/recordings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ebuchman.github.io/recordings/</guid>
      <description>Podcasts 2019-09-06: Planetary Regeneration Podcast - Ethan Buchman
2019-04-03: Epicenter - Cosmos – Launching the Internet of Blockchains 
2018-03-26: Software Engineering Daily - Consensus Systems with Ethan Buchman
2016-01-11: Epicenter Bitcoin - Tendermint - Private Modularized Blockchains
Raps and Songs I rap as &amp;ldquo;Tanuki&amp;rdquo;. See the debut album and various performances on Github.
Conferences 2019-05-06: Rebuild Conference - Stakeholders and Statemachines
2018-07-12: Edcon Toronto - A Brief History of Distributed State</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>